Washington Theater Club playbill collection, 1965-1971 MS2262
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Washington Theater Club playbill collection
1965-1971
MS2262
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
0.5 linear foot (1 box)
This collection containes Washington Theater Club playbills dating from 1965-1971.
Shakow, Alexander
Biographical/Historical note
The Washington Theater Club was formed in 1957 by the Wentworth family. On April 11, 1969, it became the first theater in Washington to win the coveted Margo Jones award for persistence in a continuing program of new play productions. Its accomplishments included the production of ten world premieres, four American premieres, thirty Washington premieres, and the introduction of sixty-four writers new to area audiences. Like other performing arts groups which flourished in the sixties but did not survive the seventies, the Theater Club came to an end in 1974. The Washington Theater Club was noted for its expansion into new areas and dramatic excellence from its modest inception in a 142-seat theater space to its two-house status with more than 9,000 subscribers.
Other Finding Aids note
For more information please see the Washington Theatre Club records, http://www.gwu.edu/gelman/spec/ead/ms2061.xml
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Gift of Alexander Shakow, 02/13/2009 (2009.007)
Arrangement note
Collection: Playbills are arranged chronologically.
Scope and Contents note
This collection containes fifty five Washington Theater Club programs. The material dates from 1965-1971.
Performing arts; Theater; Washington Theater Club
- 01/1965-12/1965 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  This folder containes playbills for the following performances. They are listed in chronological order:
  Jean Anouilh's Romeo and Jeannette, the Birthday Party, the Eccentricities of a Nightingale, Spread Eagle, Ernest in Love and the Typists and the Tiger.
- 11/1966-03/1967 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Hughie, Tiny Alice, the Marriage of Mister Mississippi and the Killer
- 04/1967-02/1968 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  the Waters of Babylon, Son of Spread Eagle, My Sweet Charlie and Caligula.
- 03/1968-09/1968 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Five Evenings, Green Julia and the Ginham Dog.
- 11/1968-01/1969 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  the Lion in Winter, Lock Up Your Daughters and Mr. Tambo, Mr. Bones.
- 11/1968-01/1969 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  the Indian Wants the Bronx, Odds and Ends, and other Caged Birds and Bread and Butter.
- 06/1969-12/1969 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Spread Eagle IV, the Moths and the Decline and Fall of the Entire World as Seen Through the Eyes of Cole Porter.
- 01/1970-05/1970 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  the Wolves, Adventures in the Skin Trade, Serenading Louie and Oliver Hailey's Continental Divide.
- 06/1970-07/1970 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Exit the King, and Before You Go.
- 10/1970-01/1970 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  the Effect of Gamma Rays on Man-in-the-Moon Marigolds, the Last Sweet Days of Isaac, a 5th of Spread Eagle and Little Boxes.
- 02/1970-06/1971 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  the Web and the Rock, Father's Day and Whores, Wars and Tin Pan Alley.